NITISH PODDAR

(217) 721-9333 • npoddar2@illinois.edu • 1005 S Lincoln Ave, 272A Leonard Hall, Urbana, IL 61801 https://github.com/nitishp1812 • https://www.linkedin.com/in/nitish-poddar-579497175/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have been exploring the field of Computer Science for the past 3 years. I am keen to gain experience in the industry, especially in the fields of Data Science, Natural Language Processing and Computer Vision.

SKILLS Proficient: Python, C++, Java, Go, MongoDB, Android

Familiar: R, HTML, CSS, SQL, React Native, Flask, Git, Node.js, JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018 **Research Assistant** / Heritage Institute Of Technology Kolkata, India

I worked under Professor Sujay Saha to learn about and come up with a solution for the problem of estimating missing values in DNA micro-arrays.

May 2017 - Jun 2017 Intern / Supertron Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

Kolkata, India I worked alongside and learned from the Android development team and contributed to an app for the Lions Club in the district and to an

app providing a similar service to Uber but with bikes.

PROJECTS

April 2019 - May 2019 **Developer** / Translation Engine (American Sign Language to English) Urbana, Illinois

I used image processing methods from OpenCV in tandem with a neural

network I trained and built to translate from the American Sign

Language to English.

Nov 2018 - Dec 2018 Co-Developer / Chatbot

Urbana, Illinois I co-developed a conversational chatbot based on the encoder decoder NLP model and deployed it using an Android application.

Jun 2017 - Jul 2017 **Developer** / NCalculator

Kolkata, India I independently developed an Android app for a scientific calculator

with functions for matrices, graphs and calculus.

EDUCATION

2018-2022(Expected) **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

Champaign, IL University Of Illinois At Urbana-Champaign

GPA: 3.96 | James Scholar Honors student | Dean's List